‎NETFLIX 出品
‎（洛杉矶 1933年）
‎妈妈给你准备了一个惊喜 ‎在前面等着你呢
Mother has a surprise for you waiting up ahead.
‎一个惊喜？
A surprise?
‎生日惊喜
A birthday surprise.
‎诺玛简 看
Norma Jeane. Look.
‎那个男人是你的父亲
That man is your father.
‎我父亲？
My father?
‎他是我父亲？
He's my father?
‎看 你父亲
Look. Your father.
‎他的名字很好听
His name is a beautiful name.
‎也很重要
And an important name.
‎但我不能说出这个名字
But it's a name I can't utter.
‎不！
No!
‎你的手黏糊糊的 不能碰这个
You mustn't touch with sticky fingers.
‎没有人知道
So no one knows.
‎也绝不能让人知道 ‎即使你已经看到了这照片
And no one must know, even that you've seen this.
‎我们俩的生活都很复杂 你明白吗？
There are complications in both our lives, you see?
‎你出生时 你父亲在很远的地方
When you were born, your father was far away.
‎即使是现在他也离得很远 ‎我很担心他的安危
He's at a great distance, even now, and I worry for his safety.
‎但在我们心里 我们已经结婚了
But in our hearts, we're wed.
‎我们是合法夫妻
We're husband and wife.
‎虽然我们蔑视传统 也不会依循于它
Though we scorn convention and will not acquiesce to it.
‎但他在哪儿？
But where is he?
‎我的手在抖
Mmm. My hands are shaking.
‎这房间在颤抖吗？
Is this room vibrating?
‎（生日快乐）
‎在加州 你…
In California,
分不清什么是“真实” ‎什么是“你的错觉”
you… can't tell what's "real" and what's "just yourself."
‎看起来很好吃 对吧？
Looks delicious, doesn't it?
‎别把口水流到我床单上
So you don't drool on my cover.
‎诺玛简 你记得 ‎谁过去睡在这儿的吗？
Do you remember, Norma Jeane, who used to sleep here?
‎在这抽屉里 你记得吗？
In this drawer? Do you remember?
‎你！
You!
‎是你 诺玛简！ ‎你以前就睡在这个抽屉里
You, Norma Jeane! You slept right in this very drawer.
‎我们当时很穷 ‎这个抽屉就是你的婴儿床
We were so poor, this drawer was your crib.
‎但对我们来说已经很好了 对吧？
But it was good enough for us, wasn't it?
‎（查理卓别林 《城市之光》）
‎我爱你 诺玛简
I love you, Norma Jeane.
‎总有一天 我会回洛杉矶与你相认
And one day, I will return to Los Angeles to claim you.
‎诺玛简？
Norma Jeane? Norma Jeane?
‎诺玛简 亲爱的 醒醒！
Norma Jeane, honey. Wake up!
‎醒醒！
Wake up!
‎来吧 上来！我们走吧！
Come on. Up, up! Let's go!
‎-我累了 ‎-跟我来
-I'm tired. -Come with me.
‎好的
Okay.
‎（好莱坞庄园）
‎别像要撒尿的小蛇一样蠕动
Stop squirming like a little snake needing to pee.
‎妈妈 如果房子烧了怎么办？ ‎我忘了拿我的老虎了
Mother? What if the house burns down? I forgot my tiger.
‎那个玩具
That toy.
回来
-Go back!
‎天啊
Oh God. Oh God.
‎天啊 我什么都看不到
Oh God, I can't see a fucking thing.
‎嘿！
Hey!
‎你到底在干什么？
What the hell are you doing?
‎我们被邀请去月桂谷顶的私人住宅
We've been invited to a private residence at the top of Laurel Canyon.
‎业主有一栋防火豪宅 ‎我女儿和我在那儿会很安全的
The owner has a fireproof mansion. My daughter and I will be safe there.
‎我不能说这个人的名字 警官 ‎但这是你们都知道的名字
I can't say this man's name, officer, but it's a name you all know.
‎他是行业巨头
He's a titan in the industry.
‎这个小女孩是他的女儿
This little girl is his daughter.
‎这是一座沙城 没什么事是能长久的
This is a city of sand, nothing will long endure,
‎但我们得去
but we are going.
‎女士 回家吧
Ma'am, go home.
‎让你女儿上床睡觉吧 好吗？ ‎已经很晚了
Put your little girl to bed, okay? It's late.
‎事实上 长官 我想近距离看看地狱
Actually, officer, I'd like to see hell close-up.
‎预览一下
A preview.
‎女士 你得调头回去
Ma'am, you need to turn around.
‎如果你需要 我可以护送你回去 ‎但是这是命令
I can give you an escort if you need one, but this is an order.
‎现在调头 否则我不得不逮捕你
If you don't turn around, I'll have to put you under arrest.
‎因为我开自己的车而逮捕我吗？
Under arrest for driving my car?
‎抱歉 警官 请别逮捕我
I'm sorry, officer. Please don't arrest me.
‎我希望你开枪杀了我
I wish you would shoot me.
‎回家吧 好吗？
Lady, look, go home, okay?
‎你喝醉嗑了药 ‎今晚没人有空处理这事
You're drunk, you're doped up, and no one's got time for this tonight.
‎你现在说的话会给你惹麻烦的
You're saying things to get you into trouble.
‎快走吧 走
Come on. Go.
‎妈妈？他在这儿吗？
Mother? Was he here?
‎我父亲？一直都在这儿吗？
My father? All this time?
‎他为什么不来看我们？
Why didn't he come to see us?
‎什么？
What? What?
‎水太烫了
It's too hot.
‎诺玛简 进浴缸里去
Norma Jeane, get in the bath.
‎你乖乖的 进浴缸里去
Be a good girl and get in the bath.
‎-水太烫了 ‎-进浴缸里去！
-It's too hot. -Get in the bath!
‎好姑娘
Good girl. Good girl. Okay.
‎因为她爱这孩子 希望她不要悲伤
Because she loved the child and wished to spare her grief.
‎因为这孩子就像 ‎是她秘密的一面 却暴露了
Because the child was her own secret self, exposed.
‎因为这孩子的父亲不希望她出生
Because the very father of the child had wished it not to be born.
‎因为他给了她钱 把钞票撒在床上
Because he had given her money, scattering bills across the bed.
‎因为他告诉她 他从不爱她
Because he told her he had never loved her.
‎她误会了
She had misunderstood.
‎因为在她怀孕前 他爱过她
Because before the pregnancy, he had loved her.
‎有了孩子之后 他就不爱了
And after, he had not.
‎因为他本来会娶她 她当时很确定
Because he would have married her. She was certain.
‎因为没人会疼爱深受诅咒的孩子
Because no one could love a child so accursed.
‎是因为你！
It's because of you!
‎因为你 他离开了！他不想要你！
You're the reason he went away! He didn't want you!
‎救命啊！帮帮我们！
Help! Help us! --Help! Help us!
‎救命啊 我妈妈病了！
Help, my mother's sick!
‎-诺玛简？ ‎-帮帮我妈妈吧
-Norma Jeane? -Help my mother.
‎克莱夫 带她进来 拿毛巾给她盖住
Clive, bring her in. Cover her.
‎-来这儿 ‎-来这儿
Come here.
‎来这儿 诺玛简
Come here, Norma Jeane.
‎你妈妈出事了吗？
-There's something wrong with your mother?
她需要帮助
-She needs help.
‎她需要帮助？
-She needs help?
‎你和我进来 诺玛简
You come inside with me, Norma Jeane.
‎我们在这儿等 好吗？
-You wait right here. Okay?
‎跟我在一起
You just stay with me.
‎你没事了 你现在没事了
You're okay. You're okay now.
‎你安全了 诺玛简
You're safe, Norma Jeane.
‎你妈妈现在好多了 ‎可以见你了 诺玛简
Your mama's well enough to see you now, Norma Jeane.
‎你妈妈一直在问你的事
Your mama's been askin' for you.
‎医生说她状态很好 可以让你去看她
The doctors say she's well enough for you to visit her.
‎我们去吗？
Shall we go?
‎她在哪儿？
Where is she?
‎她在诺尔沃克的医院里
She's in the hospital in Norwalk.
‎她现在好点了吗？
Sh… she's better now?
‎她现在还不错 可以让你探望她了
Well, she's well enough for you to visit with her.
‎克莱夫叔叔会开车带我们去
Uncle Clive is gonna take us in the car.
‎我会替你把一些东西放在手提箱里
And I'm gonna put a few things in a suitcase for you.
‎你什么都不用做
You don't have to do anything.
‎好的
Okay.
‎（洛杉矶孤儿之家协会）
‎请原谅我 诺玛简
Please forgive me, Norma Jeane.
‎现在你没有别的地方可去了
There's no other place for you right now.
‎你妈妈病了
Your mother is sick.
‎医生说她病得很严重
The doctors say that she is very sick.
‎她想伤害你
She tried to hurt you.
‎她现在不能做你的母亲
She can't be a mother to you just now.
‎我现在也不能做你的母亲
I can't be a mother to you just now.
‎但我不是孤儿
But I'm not an orphan.
‎我有母亲 也有父亲
I have a mother, and I have a father.
‎我不是孤儿
I'm not an orphan.
‎我父亲很快就会回家 他保证过的
My father is coming home soon. He promised.
‎来吧 诺玛简 快来 你乖乖的
Come on now, Norma Jeane. Come on. Be a good girl. Be a good girl.
‎不！
No!
‎拜托 诺玛简 拜托你
Please, Norma Jeane? Please?
‎-不要！ ‎-别闹了！
-No! I'm not an orphan! -Stop it! Come on!
‎-我不是孤儿！ ‎-来吧！
‎来吧！做个好女孩
Come on! Please be a good girl.
‎我不是孤儿！
I am not an orphan!
‎克莱夫 至少把行李箱拿进去 ‎你这该死的！
At least bring in the suitcases, Clive, damn you!
‎我爸爸很快就会回来！他保证过的！
My father is coming back soon! He promised!
‎不 停！
No. Stop it!
‎别哭了！停！
Stop crying! Stop!
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸
‎让她生活无忧
‎但我的爸爸在哪？
‎无论富贵贫穷 我不在乎是谁
‎如果他没有一百万 五十万也可
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸
‎我的爸爸会是你吗？
‎这光圈是你的
The circle of light is yours.
‎这是个光圈 也象征着关注
It's a circle of light and attention.
‎你把自己置于圈中
You enclose yourself in the circle.
‎无论你走到哪儿都带着它
You carry it with you wherever you go.
‎你要想象在你真实的肉体旁边的
You're going to imagine that next to your own real body,
‎是你用自己的头脑创造的
is the imaginary body of your character,
‎假想角色的身体
whom you've created with your mind.
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸
‎他银发苍苍
‎爸爸 我不知道该穿什么
Daddy, I couldn't imagine what to wear.
‎你看起来很棒
You look fine.
‎你确定吗？
Are you sure?
‎我很焦虑
I mean, I'm so jumpy.
‎5点的约会别迟到了
Just don't be late for your appointment at 5:00.
‎说得好像我会迟到一样 天啊
As if I would be late. My God.
‎你不明白吗 诺玛简？
Don't you see, Norma Jeane?
‎未来就在你手中
The future is in the palm of your hand.
‎我是玛丽莲梦露 来见扎先生
Marilyn Monroe for Mr. Z?
‎“想象一下 知道每晚
"Imagine, to know every night
‎有众多不同的人爱着你”
that differing hundreds of people love you."
‎“他们想要你”
"They want you."
‎“你属于此”
"You belong."
‎“仅此一点就值了”
"Just that alone is worth anything."
‎“无论你走到哪儿都带着它”
"You carry it with you wherever you go."
‎“这光圈是你的”
"The circle of light is yours."
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸 ‎以免她深陷泥潭
‎（总裁室 - 私人区域）
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸
‎护她安全
‎对 我们感觉就像小红帽
‎因为大灰狼饥饿难耐…
‎你不必读台词
You don't have to read.
‎我不明白
I don't understand.
‎你入选了 你是剧组演员了 ‎他钦点的玛丽莲梦露
You're in. You're cast. If your name is Marilyn Monroe.
‎对 是我
Yes, that's me.
‎但我不明白
But I don't understand.
‎你看见那个人了吗？ ‎那是制作人马克斯费边
Do you see that man? That's Max Fabian, the producer.
‎现在去为自己争取权益吧
Now go and do yourself some good.
‎他们为什么看起来总是不开心？
Why do they always look like unhappy rabbits?
‎因为他们就是不开心 ‎现在去让他开心吧
'Cause that's what they are. Now go and make him happy.
‎每个孩子都需要爸爸
‎我的爸爸会是你吗？
‎没事 诺玛简 回过神来吧 诺玛简
It's all right, Norma Jeane. Come back, Norma Jeane.
‎回到现实 诺玛简
Come back here, Norma Jeane.
‎嘿 没关系
Hey. It's okay.
‎没事的
It's okay.
‎没关系
‎没事的 诺玛简
-It's all right, Norma Jeane.
‎嘿 一切都很好
Hey. Everything's all right.
‎诺玛简？你刚才在想什么？
Norma Jeane? What were you thinking of?
‎我没想什么
I wasn't thinking.
‎或许…
Um, maybe…
‎我是在回忆？
…I was remembering?
‎（试镜 ‎片名-无需敲门》）
‎（角色-“奈尔” ‎1951年12月6日）
‎我读了剧本 整个剧本
I… I read the script, the whole script.
‎这个故事很奇怪、让人不安
It's, um… such a strange, disturbing story.
‎这个心理不平衡的女人 ‎差点杀害了一个小女孩
This mentally unbalanced woman almost killing a little girl.
‎就像陀思妥耶夫斯基的小说 ‎你会同情犯人
Like a novel by Dostoyevsky, where you feel sympathy for the criminal
‎不希望看到她受罚
and don't wish to see her punished.
‎亲爱的 你读过 ‎陀思妥耶夫斯基的书？
Oh, you've read Dostoyevsky, have you, honey?
‎是的
All right.
‎好吧 梦露小姐 我们开始吧
Well, Miss Monroe, let's, uh… let's begin.
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe?
‎你现在回去 回去
You go back now. Go back.
‎“她是你的孩子？”
"She yours?"
‎不 她不是我的孩子
No. She doesn't belong to me.
‎这不是你的房间 你回里面去睡觉
This isn't your room. You go back in there and go to sleep.
‎“她在哭”
"She's crying."
‎如果你不理他们 他们自然会停
If you don't pay any attention to them, they stop.
‎“我觉得我最好离开 ‎免得会有双胞胎从柜子里出来”
"I think I'd better leave before twins pop out of the closet."
‎但你现在没有任何离开的理由
But you haven't any reason to leave now.
‎“当然有 我想走”
"Sure, I have. I want to."
‎我跟你走
I'll go with you.
‎-我们去跳舞吧 ‎-“你有什么毛病？”
-Let's go dancing. -"What's the matter with you?"
‎“你应该留在这里照顾那孩子”
"You're supposed to be here with that kid."
‎那留下来吧
Then stay.
‎她再也不会烦你了
She won't bother you anymore.
‎“是你在烦我
"You bother me."
‎我搞不懂你”
"I can't figure you out."
‎我会按照你的想法改变自己
I'll be any way you want me to be.
‎“为什么？为什么非要跟我在一起？”
"Why? Why is it so important?"
‎因为…
Because…
‎我们注定要在一起 菲利普
I belong with you, Philip.
‎我从没想过你会回来
I didn't think you were ever coming back.
‎“我是杰德 奈尔
"I'm Jed, Nell."
‎我不是你想的那个人
"I'm not the man you think I am."
‎记得吗？
"Remember?"
‎你记得菲利普吗？”
"Remember Philip?"
‎记得
Yes.
‎“现在回想一下
"Now, think back."
‎想想
"Think."
‎他长什么样？”
"What did he look like?"
‎他有…
He had…
‎棕色的眼睛
brown eyes.
‎乌黑锃亮的头发
Shiny black hair.
‎“我不是菲利普 我是杰德 奈尔
"I'm not Philip. I'm Jed, Nell."
‎我是杰德”
"I'm Jed."
‎人的名字…
People's names…
‎你不是他
You're not him.
‎你从来都不是
You never were.
‎谢谢你 梦露小姐
Thank you, Miss Monroe.
‎拜托
Please.
‎我能再试试吗？
Can I try again?
‎我知道我能演奈尔
I… I know I could be Nell.
‎我觉得我就是奈尔
I think I am Nell.
‎她会梦游
She's a sleepwalker.
‎她看见的不是他 ‎而是她死去的未婚夫
She doesn't see him. She sees her dead fiancé.
‎她陷入了幻想
She's trapped in delusion.
‎但梦在哪里结束 ‎疯狂又在哪里开始？
But where does dreaming end and madness begin?
‎总之 爱不都是基于幻想吗？
Anyway, isn't all love based on delusion?
‎这太棒了…
It was beautiful…
‎-我很想… ‎-谢谢你 约翰 谢谢你们 先生们
-I really wanted… -Thank you, John. Thank you, gentlemen.
‎-那… ‎-我们会等你们的消息
That was, uh…We'll hear from you.
‎很糟吧？
…pretty bad, wasn't it?
‎就像…
Like, um,
‎是在看一个精神病人 可以这么说
watching a mental patient, maybe.
‎不是在演 没有技巧
Not acting. No technique.
‎像那样的人之所以会迷上表演 ‎原因显而易见
People like that, you can see why they're drawn to acting.
‎因为演员在饰演一个角色时 ‎能清楚地知道自己是谁
Because the actor in her role always knows who she is.
‎你觉得呢 老板？
What do you think, boss?
‎天啊
Sweet Jesus.
‎看看那个小姑娘的屁股
Look at the ass on that little girl.
‎（诺尔沃克州医院）
‎你确定去探望她不会太伤心吗？
Are you sure a visit with her won't be too upsetting?
‎让你妈妈伤心 ‎还是让你伤心 贝克小姐？
Upsetting to your mother or to you, Miss Baker?
‎我十年没见我妈妈了
I haven't seen my mother in ten years.
‎那是一些更棘手的病人
Those are some of our more troubled patients.
‎我们到了
Here we are.
‎妈妈
Oh, Mother.
‎妈妈？
Mother?
‎妈妈 是我 诺玛简
Mother, it's me. It's me, Norma Jeane.
‎妈妈 这儿真不错
Mother, it's so nice here.
‎这儿还不错吧？
Isn't it nice here?
‎你现在暖和点了吗？
Are you warmer now?
‎这条围巾 你戴着真漂亮
Oh, this shawl, it's so pretty on you.
‎过去这一年真是太让人兴奋了
It's been so exciting this past year.
‎太棒了 像童话一样
So wonderful. Like a fairy tale.
‎有时候 我都不敢相信
Sometimes, I can't believe it.
‎我跟制片厂签约了
I'm under contract at the studio.
‎你以前在那儿工作
Where you used to work.
‎我拍拍照就能养活自己了
I can make a living just being photographed.
‎我想这些照片里 ‎没有诺玛简的影子 对吧？
I guess there isn't any Norma Jeane, is there?
‎妈妈？
Mother?
‎你说过 我父亲是跟制片厂签了约的
My father was under contract to the studio, you said.
‎大约在1925年？
Around 1925?
‎我一直在制片厂里偷偷摸摸地 ‎试着在档案中找他的照片…
I've been sneaking around there trying to find his picture in the files--
‎我女儿在哪儿？
Where's my daughter?
‎他们说我女儿要来
They said my daughter was coming.
‎我不认识你 你是谁？
I don't know you. Who are you?
‎停
And cut.
‎对 割吧 别这么懦弱 割下去
Yes, cut. Don't be a coward. Cut.
‎动手啊！
Do it!
‎你没事吧？
You all right?
‎嘿 来吧
Hey.
‎怎么了？你还好吗？
Hey, what's wrong? You okay?
‎迪迪 没事 一切尽在掌控中 ‎我们没事 谢谢
Dee-Dee, it's okay. I have it. We're fine, thank you.
‎亲爱的
-Oh, dear.
‎嘿 没事的 一切都好 谢谢
Hey, that's all right. Everything is okay. Thank you.
‎给我们点时间
Give us a second.
‎“玛丽莲梦露 ‎冉冉升起的好莱坞新星
Marilyn Monroe, a rising new Hollywood talent
‎在这部阴暗得令人心颤的惊悚片中 ‎以突出及多变的表演证明了自己
proves herself a strong dynamic presence in this darkly disturbing thriller.
‎由理查德韦德马克领衔主演
Also starring Richard Widmark.
‎她演绎的精神失常的年轻保姆 ‎令人不寒而栗…”
Her portrayal of a mentally unbalanced young babysitter is so chillingly convincing--
‎西恩先生 在首映上 我频频闭眼
Mr. Shinn, at the premiere, I shut my eyes a lot.
‎我不敢相信那个女孩就是我
I couldn't believe that girl was me.
‎但每位观众都会觉得那就是我 奈尔
But everyone in the audience would think it was me, Nell.
‎稍后在派对上才是玛丽莲
And later at the party, Marilyn.
‎你在吃止痛片吗？
Are you on painkillers?
‎你来姨妈了？
Is it your period?
‎没 没来
No. No, it's not.
这关你什么事…
Um, what business of yours--
‎亲爱的 下一部电影会很棒的 ‎我向你保证
Sweetheart, the next film is going to be terrific, I promise you.
‎比《无需敲门》经典得多
A whole lot classier than Don't Bother,
‎我觉得这部要是没有你来演的话 ‎就是个垃圾 但不要引用我的话
which I think is a stagy piece of crap except for you, but don't quote me.
‎（洛杉矶演员圈 1952年）
‎玛丽莲值得拥有更好的
Marilyn deserves better than this.
‎玛丽莲会成为明星
Marilyn is gonna be a star.
‎这地方…
This place…
‎知道这是什么气味吗？
Know what it smells of?
‎沉闷、陈旧的爱液
Dreary old love-paste.
‎没有什么比这腐臭的 ‎陈旧的爱液更沉闷的了
Nothing more dreary than rancid old love-paste.
‎我们演过色情电影
You know, we've performed in porn films.
‎-就为了享受 不是为了钱 ‎-我没嘲笑钱 我从来不会
Just for the hell of it. Not for cash.I didn't sneer at the cash. I never do.
‎她是个正经人
-She's a prude.
‎全民金色梦幻小姐
Miss Golden Dreams of all people.
‎人的身体就是要让别人看见
The human body is meant to be seen.
‎让别人爱慕
Admired and…
‎以及渴望
desired.
‎不要像丑陋的溃烂伤口一样藏起来
Not hidden away like some ugly festering wound.
‎有很多身体应该藏起来
There's plenty of bodies that should be hidden away.
‎但是卡西 你的不需要 我的也不用
But not yours, Cassie, and not mine.
‎我们的姑娘诺玛的当然也不用
And for sure not our girl Norma's.
‎你在干什么？
What are you doing?
‎你在看她吗？
Are you looking at her?
‎你能看见她吗？
Can you see her?
‎我喜欢看镜中的自己
I like to watch myself in the mirror.
‎我甚至喜欢看自己上厕所的样子
I like to watch myself on the toilet even.
‎在我们家 我的父亲卓别林
In our household, my father, Chaplin,
‎是个神奇的人
was all the magic.
‎他把所有的目光都吸到他身上
He drew all the light into himself
‎直到我的内心除了麻木 一无所有
until there was nothing left inside me but numbness.
‎宛如沉睡
Like sleep.
‎唯有镜子能让我看见自己
Only in the mirror could I see myself.
‎我在镜子里做的一切事情
Anything I did in the mirror,
‎我都能听到人潮和他们的欢呼声
I could hear waves and waves of applause.
‎看 诺玛简
Look, Norma Jeane.
‎她在那儿
There she is.
‎你的神奇朋友
Your magic friend.
‎你在等我们吗？
Were you waiting for us?
‎诺玛？
Norma?
‎是的
Yes.
‎你渴望我们吗？
Were you starved for us?
‎对
Yes.
‎但别对我们太好
But don't be nice to us.
‎对 就像喂眼镜蛇一样
Yeah. Like feeding a cobra.
‎我对自己会避之唯恐不及
I'd use a ten-foot stick on me, myself.
‎带上我
‎让我兴奋
‎就在此刻 让我兴奋
‎（汹涌澎湃的情感…）
‎（甚至连天性都无法控制！）
‎带上我 把我抱在怀里…
‎她歌唱爱情 正如她为爱而活
She sang of love just as she lived for love.
‎她像罗蕾莱女妖一样 ‎不断引诱着男人走向永恒的毁灭
Like a Lorelei, flaunting her charms as she lured men on and on
‎炫耀她的魅力
to their eternal destruction.
‎玛丽莲梦露一跃冲上了演艺新高度
It's Marilyn Monroe, skyrocketing to new dramatic heights.
‎（致命诱惑…）
‎当一个男人将可爱的她拥入怀中
When a man took her loveliness in his arms,
‎他的性命就握在她的手中
he took his life in his hands.
‎你闻着有种廉价的感觉 ‎我知道那意味着什么
You smell like a dime store. I know what that means.
‎对 我在约会
Sure, I'm meeting somebody.
‎随便谁都行 只要他是个男人
Just anybody handy, as long as he's a man.
‎约瑟夫克顿无可救药地迷恋她
Joseph Cotten, helpless in her siren spell.
‎那不是我们的诺玛
That is not our Norma.
‎那不是我们的小鱼儿
That's not our little Fishie.
‎但她永远都不会 ‎彻底属于他或任何男人
But she could never be his nor any man's completely.
‎这个念头让他发疯
And that thought whipped him into a frenzy
‎这让荧幕一阵轰鸣 充满悬念
that makes the screen thunder with unparalleled suspense.
‎（激情可以把人带到世界之巅！）
‎（也可让人坠入谷底！）
‎（尼亚加拉和玛丽莲梦露）
‎（全世界最引人入胜的两个景致！）
‎我猜她很美
She is pretty, I guess.
‎但那不是我 对吗？
But it isn't me, is it?
‎（《真实故事》）
‎等人们发现的时候怎么办？
How about when people find out?
‎宝贝 我们发现了 但我们仍然爱你
Hell, baby, we found out, and we still love you.
‎我只是…我希望能躲在你们的怀抱里
I just… I wish I could just hide in your arms.
‎永远在你们怀里
Forever and ever in your arms.
‎但你不是认真的 诺玛
But you don't mean that, Norma.
‎女演员需要被人看到
An actress wants to be seen.
‎女演员需要被众多人喜爱
An actress wants to be loved by a multitude of people.
‎不 我真正想要的是你
No. What I really want is you.
‎你太贴心了
You're so sweet.
‎我讨厌这照片 我看起来像个混蛋
I hate this one. I look like an asshole.
‎（《机密》）
‎我的嘴巴张开 气喘吁吁的样子
With my mouth open, like I'm panting.
‎“年轻的花花公子小查理卓别林
"Young men-about-town, Charlie Chaplin Jr.
‎和小爱德华G罗宾逊
and Edward G. Robinson Jr."
‎以及金发性感女郎玛丽莲梦露
"And blonde sexpot, Marilyn Monroe."
‎三人行”
"A threesome."
‎多粗俗啊
How vulgar.
‎“性感女郎”
"A sexpot."
‎“性感女郎”是什么？
What is a "sexpot"?
‎这是性感女郎吗？
Is this the sexpot?
‎-不！ ‎-或者是这个？
-No! -Or this?
‎不！
No! No!
No!
‎（最高机密 ‎梦露卷入三角关系）
‎我不希望你和他们 ‎在公共场合一起露面
I don't want you seen in public with them, Norma Jeane.
‎那私下呢？
And in private?
‎私下
In private…
‎也最好不要
take precautions.
‎西恩先生 那太残忍了
Oh, Mr. Shinn, that's so cruel.
‎粗鲁且残忍 而且你…你知道的
It's crude and cruel. And you… you know it.
‎我只是在为你的事业和幸福考虑
I'm just thinking of your career and your well-being.
‎你是在为玛丽莲考虑
You're thinking of Marilyn.
‎-对 ‎-她的事业
-Yes. -Her career.
‎对 还有她的幸福
Yes. And her well-being.
‎她一点都不幸福
She doesn't have any well-being.
‎她只是个职业
She's only a career.
‎他们知道我是诺玛
They know I'm Norma.
‎不是玛丽莲
Not Marilyn.
‎他们理解我
They understand me.
‎我理解你 我创造了你
I understand you. I invented you.
‎诺玛
Oh, Norma.
‎我猜我确实爱你
I guess I do love you.
‎你和艾迪在一起时我会吃醋
I'm jealous of you and Eddy.
‎我嫉妒任何看着你的人
Jealous of anybody who looks at you.
‎若我有朝一日会爱上一个女人
If I could love any woman,
‎那一定会是你
it'd be you.
‎当你说你爱我的时候
When you say you love me
‎当你看着我的时候
and when you look at me…
‎你看到的人到底是谁？
who do you see, truly?
‎小卓别林吗？你看到的是他吗？
The Little Tramp? Do you see him?
‎不
No.
‎我看到的只是你
I see only you.
‎人们觉得当查理卓别林的儿子很幸运
People think it's a blessing being Charlie Chaplin's son.
‎像童话一样 我是国王的儿子
Like it's a fairy tale, and I'm the king's son.
‎但我们被诅咒了 艾迪和我
But we're cursed, Eddy and me.
‎我们是从来不想要我们的男人的后裔
We're juniors… of men who never wanted us.
‎但至少你们俩有父亲
But at least you two have fathers.
‎至少你们知道自己是谁
At least you know who you are.
‎我们在出生前就知道自己是谁了
Oh, we knew who we were before we were born.
‎你从不知道自己的父亲
You never knew your father.
‎所以你是自由的
So you're free.
‎你可以创造自己
You can invent yourself.
‎我爱你的名字
I love your name.
‎玛丽莲梦露
-Marilyn Monroe. -Mm-hmm.
‎太假了 我喜欢
-It's so totally phony.-I love it.
‎就像你给了自己新生一样
Like you gave birth to yourself.
‎因为他的眼睛
Because of his eyes.
‎他拥有最美的眼睛
He had the most beautiful eyes.
‎因为他会用这眼睛注视着我
Because he'd gazed upon me with those eyes.
‎这深情而深邃的眼睛
Haunting, soulful eyes.
‎很久以前 在母亲的公寓的墙上 ‎也有这么一双眼睛
From a wall of Mother's long-ago apartment.
‎因为他会看着我说…
Because he would say, seeing me…
‎我一见到你就看出来了
I knew you as soon as I saw you.
‎你没有父亲
Fatherless.
‎像我一样
Like me.
‎然后你妈妈被抛弃了
And then your mother abandoned…
‎被人羞辱
and debased.
‎像我妈妈一样
Like mine.
‎因为他会爱我 和其他男人的爱不同
Because he would love me as other men would not.
‎其他男人也做不到
Or could not.
‎我们像双胞胎
As a twin.
‎是灵魂伴侣
With his soul.
‎那是双子座
There's Gemini.
‎看见了吗？
See?
‎诺玛和我像双子座一样
Both Norma and I are Geminis.
‎命中注定的双胞胎
The fated twins.
‎哪里？
Where?
‎-我没看见 在哪儿？ ‎-那儿
-I don't see it. Where? -There.
‎这一切有数十亿年的历史了
It's all billions of years old.
‎难以想象的广阔
Unimaginably vast.
‎然而它是从什么开始的？
Yet it began out of what?
‎肉眼几乎看不见的微小颗粒
Particles so small it couldn't be seen by the human eye.
‎看看上面的它们 如此明亮耀眼
Look at them up there, shining so brightly.
‎然而每一颗都那么孤单
And yet, each one is so very much alone.
‎我会为此干一杯
I'll drink to that.
‎我们发誓吧 我们三个人
Let's vow, okay? The three of us.
‎永远都会像现在一样爱着彼此
To always love each other like right now.
‎如果需要 我们会为彼此而死
And to die for each other, if needed.
‎我们是个三角形
We're a triangle.
‎三角形不能一分为二 ‎它比两个人坚强
A triangle can't be divided in two, like two can be.
‎我们是双子座 我们三个人
We're the Gemini, the three of us.
‎就像双胞胎 但我们是三个人
Like twins. But there's three.
‎敬双子座
To the Gemini.
‎天啊 我就知道
Oh God, I knew.
‎我就知道 ‎我最近感觉很肿胀、很开心
I guess I knew. I've been feeling so swollen and so happy.
‎亲爱的 你很健康
My dear, you're healthy.
‎一切都会变好的
Everything's gonna be fine.
‎我说 我很开心
I'm happy, I said.
‎我想要这个孩子
I want this baby.
‎我和我的丈夫试了很多年了
My husband and I have been trying for years.
‎嘿 诺玛
Hey, Norma.
‎怎么了？你看起来很紧张而且很开心
What is it? You look… fraught. And happy.
‎哦 诺玛…
Oh, Norma…
‎你觉得你怀上了？
You think you are?
‎-是我想的那样吗？ ‎-对！
-Is this what I think it is? -Yes!
‎天啊！
Oh, man!
‎你们为我高兴吗？
Are you happy for me?
‎我们？我是说双子座
Us? The Gemini, I mean?
‎-开心！ ‎-开心！
-Yes! -Yes!
‎就像电影一样
It's like the movies.
‎那种只在电影里发生的事
The kind of thing that only happens in the movies.
‎什么？
What?
‎那只小老虎
That little tiger.
‎我以前有过一个类似的
I had one like him once.
‎那是很久以前 我还小的时候
A long time ago when I was a little girl.
‎宝宝的第一个玩具
Baby's first plaything.
‎真可爱
Cute.
‎卡西 你要带我们去哪儿？
Cass, where are you taking us?
‎我想回家
I wanna go home.
‎好吗？
Right?
‎宝宝太困了
Baby's so sleepy.
‎这是要让宝宝看到的景色
Oh, this is a vision for baby to see.
‎等等嘛
Just wait.
‎诺玛 你可以选择看或者不看…
Norma, you can look or not,
但她就在那儿
but… there she is.
-玛丽莲 ‎-玛丽莲
Mmm… Marilyn.-Marilyn.
‎我不能接这个角色 抱歉
I can't take the role.I'm sorry.
‎你还在听电话吗？
Are you still on the line?
‎出什么事了吗？
Is something wrong?
‎没 没出事 ‎我只是不能接 现在不行
No, nothing's wrong.-I just can't.-Not now
‎现在不行？为什么现在不行？
Not now? Why not now?
‎你现在是票房新秀
You're the newest box office sensation now.
‎扎努克为你买下了《绅士爱美人》
Zanuck has bought Gentlemen Prefer Blondes for you.
‎他想让你在里面大放异彩
He wants it as a showcase for you.
‎我能拿到多少钱？
How much would I get?
‎你的合同工资
Your contract salary.
‎一周五百
Five hundred a week.
‎简拉塞尔能拿多少？
How much would Jane Russell get?
‎交易待定中
The deal is pending.
‎拉塞尔正在另一个制片厂拍戏 ‎得借她过来
And Russell has to be lent by another studio.
‎对 但是多少钱？
Yes, but how much?
‎-金额还没定下来 ‎-多少钱？
The figures aren't finalized.How much?
‎他们要价十万
They're asking… $100,000.
‎十万？
$100,000?
‎我拿五千 而简拉塞尔能拿十万？
I'll get about $5,000, and Jane Russell gets $100,000?
‎而我演《绅士爱美女》中的 ‎金发女人？
And I'm playing the blonde in Gentlemen Prefer Blondes?
‎这太侮辱人了
That's an insult.
‎-我要挂电话了 再见 ‎-玛丽莲 等等
-I'm gonna hang up now. Goodbye. - Marilyn, wait.
‎让玛丽莲去死吧 她不在这儿
Fuck Marilyn. She's not here.
‎致我的宝宝
"To My Baby."
‎在你身上
In you
‎世界重生
The world is born anew
‎在你之前 一无所有
Before you There was none
‎你想当外婆吗？
How'd you like to be a grandmother?
‎现在是哪一年了？
What year is it?
‎我们到了什么时候？
What time did we travel to?
‎妈妈 现在是1953年5月
Mother, it's May 1953.
‎我是诺玛简
I'm Norma Jeane.
‎我来这儿照顾你
I'm here to take care of you.
‎但你的头发太白了
But your hair is so white.
‎当你生下我的时候 妈妈 ‎我猜你当时没结婚
When you had me, Mother, you weren't married, I guess.
‎你没有男人支持你
You didn't have a man supporting you.
‎可你却生下了一个孩子
And you had a baby.
‎那太勇敢了
That was so brave.
‎换成其他女孩…
Another girl would've…
‎可能会打掉孩子
well, you know, gotten rid of it.
‎打掉我
Of me.
‎那我根本不会在这儿 ‎也就不会有玛丽莲了
And I wouldn't be here at all. There wouldn't be any Marilyn.
‎她现在很出名了
And she's getting so famous now.
‎粉丝来信、电报…
Fan letters, telegrams.
‎陌生人的花接踵而至
Flowers from strangers.
‎但你当时很勇敢
But you were brave.
‎你做了正确的事
You did the right thing.
‎你生下了你的孩子
You had your baby.
‎你生下了我
You had me.
‎她得的是一种神秘的疾病
Hers is a mystery illness.
‎一种人们并不真正理解的病
An illness no one truly understands.
‎一种症状综合症
A syndrome of symptoms.
‎这是遗传的吗？
Is it inherited?
‎什么？
Excuse me?
‎我妈妈的病 是不是…
My mother's illness, are you…
‎是不是…
Are you…
‎是不是与生俱来的呢？
Are you born with it in your blood?
‎好吧 玛丽莲 ‎我会把你的电话转接伊薇特
All right, Marilyn, what I'll do is I'll turn you over to Yvet.
‎你记得伊薇特吗？她会帮你的
You remember Yvet? She'll help you.
‎玛丽莲？
Marilyn?
‎-我需要帮助 我迫切需要帮助 ‎-亲爱的 我会安排的
-I need help. I need help so badly. -Dear, I'll make the arrangements.
‎计划明早8点出发 ‎我们派车去你家接你
Plan on tomorrow morning at 8:00 a.m. You'll be picked up at home.
‎（停）
‎拜托 我想回去
Please, I wanna go back.
‎嘿 我改变主意了
-Hey, I've changed my mind.
‎我改变想法了
My mind's my own to change.
‎哦 刺眼的光
Oh, the bright lights.
‎亲爱的 我们会照顾好你的
You're in good hands, dear.
‎拜托 你们没听到吗？我改变想法了
Please, won't you listen? I've changed my mind.
‎求你们了 别 你们不听我说话吗？
Please, don't. Won't you listen?
‎这会让你陷入昏睡
This will put you in twilight sleep.
‎不 我想回去
No, I… wanna go back.
‎不 等等
No. Wait.
‎等等！不！
Wait! Wait! No! No!
‎诺玛！
‎不！
No!
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe?
‎再见 宝贝
‎记得你是我的宝贝
‎梦露小姐
Miss Monroe.
‎梦露小姐 是时候了
Miss Monroe, it's time.
‎我一直很孤独
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe?
‎不会有其他人
‎我的名声和财富源自我的运气
I'm one of the winners of the American lottery.
‎我是知道的 我为此很感激
I know it. I'm grateful for it.
‎我从不认为这是理所当然的 ‎棒球是我的生命
And I never take it for granted. Baseball was my life.
‎棒球是我改变人生的入场券
Baseball was my ticket up and out.
‎现在…
And now, well,
‎我退役了
I'm retired.
‎我有很多事要做 代言…
I mean, I have plenty to do, you know, endorsements and… personal appearances,
‎私人露面和顾问委员会会议
advisory board meetings.
‎我猜我听起来像个傻瓜
I guess I sound like a sap.
‎不会
No. No. No, no.
‎感觉一定很奇怪吧 毕竟你得做个…
It must be awfully strange to be a…
‎嗯…
well… a hero.
‎英雄
‎而且你不像是退役了
Anyway, you don't seem retired.
‎经常能在报纸里看见关于你的报道
You're in the paper so much.
‎见报率不及你的一半 玛丽莲
Well, not half as much as you, Marilyn.
‎谁 我吗？
Who, me?
‎嗯…
Well…
‎那只是制片厂的宣传
That's just studio publicity.
‎它们很糟
Oh, they're awful.
‎他们会胡编乱造
The things they make up.
‎我知道做这一行应该习惯于此
I know you're supposed to get used to it.
‎但我就是不习惯
But I just can't.
‎这太令人伤心了
It really hurts.
‎你怎么开始的？
How'd you get your start?
‎开始什么？
What start?
‎开始演艺之路
In movies.
‎开始当演员
In acting.
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎我…
I…
‎我猜…
I… I guess…
‎我猜我是被人挖掘的
I guess I was discovered.
‎被挖掘 怎么挖掘的？
-Oh, discovered. How?
‎我们也许应该走了
Maybe we should leave.
‎我害怕这里的一些人
I'm afraid of some of the people here.
‎嘿
Hey.
‎我知道那是什么感觉
I know what it's like…
‎知道孤独是什么感觉
to be lonely…
‎追求更好的生活是什么感觉
to want a better life.
‎一个美好而简单的生活
A good, simple life.
‎一个体面的生活
A decent life.
‎我只是想再次从零开始
I just wanna begin again from zero.
‎我想住在…
I wanna live in…
‎我想住在另一个世界 远离好莱坞
I wanna live in another world. Away from Hollywood.
‎我想住在…
I wanna live in…
‎契诃夫！
…Chekhov!
‎我想搬去纽约
I wanna move to New York.
‎学习表演
And study acting.
‎认真的表演
Serious acting.
‎在电影里 ‎他们会把你的片段剪成碎片
In the movies, they chop you all to bits.
‎剪啊剪 这是个拼图游戏
Cut, cut, cut. It's a jigsaw puzzle.
‎但这个拼图并不由你拼出来
But you're not the one to put the pieces together.
‎但你是拼图的一部分
Oh, but to live in a part.
‎在里面 直到每晚电影闭幕
To just be in it till the closing curtain every night.
‎但我主要是…
But mostly, I…
‎我想安顿下来
I wanna settle down.
‎像任何女孩一样
Like any girl.
‎拥有一个家
And have a family.
‎我非常爱孩子
Oh, I love children so.
‎我很想要孩子
I'm crazy about babies.
‎有人死了吗？
Did somebody die?
‎这些是什么？
What is all this?
‎这些花
These flowers.
‎我是一具尸体吗？
Am I a corpse?
‎这是殡仪馆吗？
Is this a funeral home?
‎我是这个玛丽莲梦露的奴隶
I'm a slave to this Marilyn Monroe.
‎我原以为是来乘坐豪华邮轮的
I signed up for a luxury cruise,
‎却落得跟罗莉拉一样 ‎在统舱里拼命地划船
but like Lorelei Lee, I'm in fucking steerage, paddling.
‎梦露小姐 你这话不是认真的
Now, Miss Monroe, you don't mean a word of what you say.
‎如果你不是玛丽莲 你会成为谁呢？
If you weren't Marilyn, who'd you be?
‎梦露小姐 你真残忍
Miss Monroe, you're cruel.
‎我们每个人 世界上的每个人
Every one of us, everybody in the world,
‎都愿意不顾一切地成为你 你知道的
would give their right arm to be you, and you know it.
‎我知道
Oh, I do.
‎“玛丽莲 你一直以来都是甜心”
"Marilyn, you are the sweetheart of this and any other month."
‎“玛丽莲 你是个婊子 ‎一个金发荡妇
"Marilyn, you are a whore, a blonde tramp."
‎没有人会爱你 你这恶心的荡妇
"Nobody will ever love you, you disgusting tramp."
‎离我们的收音机、电视、电影远点
"Get off our radio, television, and out of our movies."
‎你在毒害我们的孩子
"You're poisoning our children."
‎不是粉丝”
"Not a fan."
‎像影评人
Like movie critics.
‎有些人爱玛丽莲 有些人恨玛丽莲
Some of them love Marilyn, some of them hate Marilyn.
‎那跟我有什么关系呢？
What's that got to do with me?
‎对 她是本月头号婊子
Yes.
‎-怀特利！ ‎-她是个甜美的小荡妇
-Whitey!
‎我会写封信 并贴上邮票
‎梦露小姐 我觉得这是一封密件
Miss Monroe, this is a confidential letter, I think.
‎他的鸡巴像棒球棍一样 抱歉
He's got a bat for a cock. Sorry.
‎“亲爱的诺玛简
"Dear Norma Jeane."
‎这可能是有史以来 ‎我写过的最难的信”
"This is possibly the most difficult letter I have ever penned."
‎说实话 我不知道为什么 ‎我要在这么多年后 现在来联系你
Honestly, I… I do not know why I'm contacting you now
after so many years.
‎事实上 我得了心脏病
The truth is, I have suffered a heart attack,
‎我严肃地反思了我的人生
and I have contemplated my life with gravity.
‎我的一些行为 我并不引以为傲
I cannot say I am proud of my behavior in all cases.
‎是他
Oh, it's him.
‎我是你的父亲 诺玛简
I am your father, Norma Jeane.
‎我面前有玛丽莲梦露
And I have here before me
‎在新《佳丽》杂志的一篇采访
an interview with Marilyn Monroe in the new Pageant.
‎读到这个采访 我泪流满面
Reading it, it brought tears to my eyes
‎你说你妈妈进了医院
when you said that your mother has been hospitalized,
‎而你不知道你父亲是谁
and you do not know your father.
‎虽然你每时每刻都在等他
Although you await him with every passing hour.
‎我可怜的女儿
Oh, my poor daughter.
‎天啊
Oh God.
‎我以前不知道
-I did not know.
‎是他
-Oh, it's him.
‎我就知道
I knew.
‎这些年来 他在关注我
Watching over me all these years.
‎我能感觉到
I felt it.
‎我会再跟你联系的 诺玛简 ‎我会亲自前来
I will contact you again soon, Norma Jeane, in person.
‎所以来找我吧 我的宝贝女儿…
So look for me, my precious daughter,
‎在你人生中一个特殊的场合…
upon a special occasion in your life
‎我们父女可以庆祝我们久违的爱
where both father and daughter can celebrate our long-denied love.
‎你泪流满面的父亲
Your tearful father.
‎玛丽莲！
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎（简拉塞尔 玛丽莲梦露 ‎《绅士爱美女》）
‎玛丽莲！
Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎能占用你一点时间吗？谢谢
Can I have a moment of your time, please? Thank you.
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎玛丽莲！
‎我刚知道
I've just learned.
‎今晚一定要一个人回你的酒店套房
Be sure to go alone to your hotel suite tonight.
‎有个特别的人在那儿等你
Someone special will be waiting for you there.
‎特别的人？
Someone special? Oh.
‎是我父亲吗？
Is it my father?
‎玛丽莲 跟你的广播听众说说 ‎你今晚寂寞吗？
Marilyn, tell our radio audience. Are you lonely tonight?
‎你们俩什么时候结婚？
When are you two gonna get married?
‎结婚？
Married?
‎不
No.
‎他在这儿吗？我父亲？
Is he here? My father?
‎这就像一部冗长而困惑的 ‎电影的快乐大结局
It's like a happy ending of a long, confused movie.
‎你的父亲？
Your father?
‎我知道我有一个特别的约会
I understand that I have a special date?
‎在派对之后 就在我酒店套房里？
After the party, in my hotel suite?
‎法国人总爱为爱情献身
‎他们热衷决斗争胜
‎但我喜欢活着的男人
‎给我昂贵的珠宝首饰
‎执手轻吻
‎或许有些欧陆情调
‎但钻石是女孩最好的朋友
‎热吻也许美妙
‎但它不能支付你简陋公寓的房租
‎或者帮你在自动贩卖机买饮料
‎随着女孩变老 男人越发冷淡
‎我们最终都会失去魅力
‎但无论如何切割 这些石头永不变形
‎钻石是女孩最好的朋友…
‎爸爸
Oh, Daddy.
‎屏幕上的那个人不是我
That thing up on the screen, it isn't me.
‎蒂芙尼！
‎卡地亚！
‎布莱克斯塔尔！
‎弗雷斯特格雷姆！
‎跟我说说 海瑞温斯顿 ‎告诉我一切！
‎或许有一天 ‎年轻女孩也需要律师的关照
‎但钻石是女孩最好的朋友
‎好了
‎为了这一幕 你杀了你自己的孩子？
For this, you killed your baby?
‎爸爸？
Daddy?
‎宝贝
Baby.
‎是你
Oh, it's you.
‎玛丽莲 我…
Marilyn, I…
‎我只想让你开心
I just want you to be happy.
‎我很开心
I am happy.
‎我这辈子都很开心
I've been happy all my life.
‎玛丽莲 我们爱着彼此
Marilyn, we love each other.
‎是时候结婚了
It's time we were married.
‎对 我猜是的
Yes, I guess.
‎嘿…
Hey… Hey. Hey.
‎我太爱你了
I just love you so much.
‎我只是想保护你免受那些豺狼伤害
I just want to protect you from all these jackals.
‎我想带你远离这一切
I want to take you away from all of this.
‎好啊
Yeah.
‎在你身上 世界重生
In you, the world is born anew
‎两人一起
As two
‎在你之前…
Before you
‎只有一人
There was but one
‎就这样？
-That's it, huh?
‎这就是整首诗吗？
-Is that the whole poem? -Huh?
‎-对 ‎-嗯 这很棒 亲爱的
-Yeah. -Well, it's good, honey.
‎人们会自己做意面？
People make spaghetti?
‎我是说 这不是店里才能买到的吗？
I mean, not just in a store?
‎这闻起来太香了
That smells delicious.
‎她不会做饭
‎我能试试吗？
Can I try it?
‎这是吃的吗？
Is this to eat?
‎我意思是 站着吃？
I mean, standing up?
‎玛丽莲 当电影明星是什么样的？
So, Marilyn, what's it like being a movie star?
‎我不是明星
I'm not a star.
‎我只是个普通的金发女郎
I'm just some blonde.
‎这头发是真的吗？
So the hair's real?
‎不是
No, no.
‎爸爸 太吓人了
Daddy, it's so scary
‎在真实生活中与人相处
how a scene with actual people
‎人来人往 永无止尽
just goes on and on.
‎就像在公交车上一样
Like on a bus.
‎有什么方法能停止吗？
What's to stop it?
‎或者…
Or…
‎或者如何弄清楚人们的意图
Or how to figure out what people mean
‎而他们可能没什么特别的意思
when probably they don't mean anything.
‎不像剧本一样精心编排
Not like a script.
‎只是毫无意义的谈话
There's no point.
‎自然而然地发生
It just happens.
‎就像天气一样？
Like the weather?
‎亲爱的 在拳击里…
You know, honey, in boxing,
‎当一个人被打得很惨的时候
they say, "That got his attention"…
‎人们说：“这引起了他的注意”
when a guy gets hit hard.
‎重点在于注意力 亲爱的 要专注
Well, it's about attention, honey. It's about concentration.
‎如果你不够专注 你…
And if you don't have that…
‎我可以找人弄你们 王八蛋
I could have you hurt, you cocksuckers.
‎嘿 哟
-Hey, now.
‎这态度可不对
That's not the right attitude.
‎我们跟你是一伙的
I mean, we're on your side.
‎也站在女士这一边 她真的是个…
And the lady's too. She's a real…
‎很高级的女士
High-class lady, in fact.
‎我们强烈地认为
What we feel, strongly,
‎这些不良照片应该远离市场…
is that these, uh, negatives, well, should be off the market.
‎那样它们就不能被滥用
So they can't be misappropriated.
‎他妈的在哪儿…
Where the fuck is…
‎嗨 爸爸 你去哪儿了？
Hi, Daddy. Where'd you go to?
‎哦 爸爸 这是我的错
Oh, Daddy. It's my fault.
‎我不知道房间怎么变成这样了 ‎我猜我病了
I don't know how the room got this way. I've been sick, I guess.
‎这些照片 那就是你 一具肉体
Those photos. That's what you are. Meat.
‎爸爸 不
Daddy, no.
‎我不希望如此
I don't want to be.
‎告诉他们你不演
Tell them you won't.
‎这部新电影？不演
This new movie? No deal.
‎爸爸 我得工作
Daddy, I have to work.
‎这是我的生命
It's my life.
‎告诉他们你想要更好的角色
You tell them you want better roles.
‎更严肃的角色 告诉他们你要退出
More serious roles. You tell them you're quitting.
‎告诉他们你丈夫让你退出
You tell them your husband says you're quitting.
‎好
Yes.
‎好 我会告诉他们
Yes, I will tell them.
‎你不知道我有多爱你吗？ ‎你不明白吗？
Don't you see how much I love you? Don't you understand?
‎我知道
I know.
‎我不忍心看到你这样作贱自己
I can't bear to see you cheapen yourself like that.
‎最后我只是为这个生物感到遗憾
I just felt so sorry for the creature at the end.
‎“为这个生物感到遗憾？”
"Sorry for the creature"?
‎你要他做什么？娶那个女孩？
What'd you want him to do? Marry the girl?
‎他长得确实有点吓人 ‎但他并没有坏透顶
He was kind of scary-looking, but he wasn't really all bad.
‎我想他只是渴望一点感情 ‎你知道吗？
I think he just craved a little affection, you know?
‎一种被爱、被需要、被渴望的感觉
A sense of being loved and needed and wanted.
‎这个观点非常有趣
That's a very interesting point of view.
‎你感受到地铁的微风了吗？ ‎真舒服 不是吗？
You feel the breeze from the subway? Isn't it delicious?
‎脚踝感觉凉凉的吧？
Sort of cools the ankles, doesn't it?
‎你觉得现在做什么会很有趣？
What do you think would be fun to do now?
‎停！
And cut!
‎真舒服 不是吗？
Isn't it delicious?
‎爸爸？
Daddy?
‎爸爸 天啊 抱歉…
Daddy, gosh, I'm sorry.
‎-让你等了这么久 ‎-她来了
-Keeping you waiting so long. -There she is.
‎你为自己而骄傲？
You proud of yourself, hmm?
‎不
No.
‎你为自己而骄傲吗？
Are you proud of yourself, huh?
‎-爸爸 不… ‎-别碰我
-Daddy, don't… -Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
‎-请别… ‎-你很得意吧？
-Please… -Proud of yourself?
‎-什么？ ‎-不
-What? Huh? Huh? -No.
‎-我明天要工作 ‎-把你的私处露给所有人看？
-I'm workin' tomorrow. -Showing off your crotch?
‎拜托别
-Please don't. -Huh? Huh?
‎你觉得我吃那套吗？是吗？
You think that shit works on me? Think that works on me? Oh, yeah?
‎所有人都会知道你他妈是个婊子！
Everybody, they're gonna fuckin' know what a fuckin' whore you are!
‎操 起来！
Fuckin' get up! Huh? Huh?
‎臭婊子！
-You fucking whore! Huh?
‎来这儿！
-Get over here! Get over here!
‎我亲爱的女儿 诺玛简
My dear daughter, Norma Jeane.
‎我没有看你的新电影
I did not see your new movie.
‎那粗俗的标题和宣传
Its vulgar title and publicity attending it,
‎在那些丑化你的巨型广告牌上
these giant billboards of your crude likeness
‎你的裙子飘起来 ‎让全世界看你的私处
posed with your dress lifted up for all the world to see your private parts,
‎这一切让我不想买票看你的表演
did not make me wish to purchase a ticket.
‎操…
-Fuckin'… Huh?
‎我本来希望见见你的丈夫
I had hoped to meet your husband.
‎我一直是他的崇拜者
I've long been an admirer of his.
‎我很失望你跟如此一流的运动员
I was disappointed that your marriage to such a stellar athlete
‎以离婚收场 而且宣传如此拙劣
ended in divorce and such ugly publicity.
‎幸好你们没有孩子 他们不必受侮辱
At least there are no children to reap the shame.
‎（玛格达 1930年）
‎我的玛格达
My Magda.
‎（剧院后门）
‎我的玛格达
My Magda.
‎玛格达
Magda. Magda. Magda.
Magda.
‎（纽约城 1955年）
‎玛丽莲梦露？
Marilyn Monroe?
‎在这儿？
Here?
‎玛格达？她来演？
Magda? Her?
‎“当我梦到那儿的时候 ‎我梦到了洗衣房的气味
"When I dream of back there, I dream of the smell of laundry."
‎浴缸里满是水 我写的诗 ‎《玛格达》浸湿了 漂在水面
"The tub overflowing and the poem I wrote, 'Magda,' floating, soaked."
‎我疯了似地试着捞起纸页
"I'm frantically trying to collect the pages
‎在墨水褪去前 ‎在诗歌在我手中分崩离析前”
before the ink runs in streaks and the poem comes apart in my hands."
‎他爱上她了
He's in love with her.
‎“这是我写给她的话…
"These words I wrote her…"
‎两百个字
"Two hundred words."
‎一种祈祷
"A kind of… prayer."
‎大约40年后 我在布鲁克林醒来
"And I wake in Brooklyn, nearly 40 years later,
‎我的心脏在胸腔跳动着
my heart knocking in my chest."
‎我记得她的脸 微微泛红
"And I remember her face, blushing,
‎她那双美丽的大眼睛 ‎从诗中抬起头 说…”
and her beautiful wide-set eyes looking up from the poem, and saying…"
‎不是我的玛格达
Not my Magda.
‎（玛丽莲梦露 汤姆伊威尔 ‎出演《七年之痒》）
‎玛格达是我自己的初恋
Magda was my own first love.
‎我们从未做过爱
Never consummated.
‎我们甚至没公开
Never even really declared.
‎如果她还活着
She would be,
‎她现在应该五十多岁了
if she was even still alive, in her… in her mid-fifties.
‎美丽的玛格达
Beautiful Magda.
‎中年女人
Middle-aged.
‎我…
I…
‎关于玛格达 我有一些想法
I had some ideas about Magda,
‎如果你感兴趣的话
if you're interested.
‎当然了 我很感兴趣
Of course I'm interested.
‎你这么用心非常好
It's very good of you to care.
‎这姑娘 玛格达 ‎她就像《三姐妹》中的娜塔莎
Um, this girl, Magda, she's like Natasha in The Three Sisters.
‎就是因为裙子颜色不对 ‎被人嘲笑那个
The one they laugh at because her dress is the wrong color.
‎不过玛格达被人嘲笑 ‎是因为她说的英语
Except, with Magda, it's the way she speaks English.
‎谁告诉你的？
Who told you that?
‎什么？
What?
‎关于《三姐妹》和我的剧的事？
About The Three Sisters and my play?
‎-没人 ‎-卡赞？
-Nobody. -Kazan?
‎说我受了那部作品的影响？
That I'd been influenced?
‎不是
Uh, no.
‎不 我自己读的剧本
No, I read the play myself.
‎我总觉得我…
I always thought I…
‎我总觉得我可以演娜塔莎
I always thought I could play Natasha.
‎我在想 契诃夫塑造的娜塔莎 他…
I was thinking, what Chekhov does with Natasha, he… he…
他会让你惊讶…
He… he surprises you,
‎因为娜塔莎原来如此坚强、狡猾
because Natasha turns out to be so strong and devious.
‎而且残忍
And cruel.
‎但你的玛格达 她没有大的变化
But your Magda, she never changes much.
‎她一直都很好
She's always so good.
‎是的
Yes.
‎玛格达很好
Magda is good.
‎她的原型就是个好人
Was good. The original.
‎她决不会想做个残忍的人
She wouldn't dream of being cruel.
‎对
Yeah.
‎你对玛格达有其他的想法吗？
And, uh, you have any other thoughts about Magda?
‎我在想…
One thing I was thinking,
‎玛格达应该不识字
Magda wouldn't know how to read.
‎伊萨克把他的诗给她看 ‎她只是假装在读
Isaac shows his poem to her, and she's only pretending to read it.
‎天啊
Oh my God.
‎她是文盲 就是这样
She was illiterate. That's what it was.
‎当然了
Of course.
‎谢谢你
Well, thank you. Thank you.
‎我应该叫你玛丽莲 对吧？
I… I suppose I should call you Marilyn, shouldn't I?
‎还是那只是艺名吗？
Or is that just a stage name?
‎你可以叫我诺玛
You could call me Norma.
‎那是我真正的名字
That's my true name.
‎如果你喜欢的话 我可以叫你诺玛
I could call you Norma, if you prefer.
‎或者我可以叫你…
Or, uh, I could call you, uh…
‎我的玛格达
my Magda.
‎我很喜欢
I'd like that.
‎我的秘密玛格达
My secret Magda.
‎好
Yes.
‎但其他人在旁边的时候 ‎或许该叫玛丽莲
But maybe "Marilyn" when others are around
‎这样就不会有人误解了
so there wouldn't be any misunderstandings.
‎别人在身边的时候 ‎你叫我什么都不重要
When others are around, it doesn't matter what you call me.
‎你可以吹口哨
You can whistle.
‎你可以叫我：“嘿 你”
You can call me, "Hey, you."
‎嘿 你
Hey, you.
‎（亚瑟米勒和玛丽莲梦露即将结婚）
‎所有猜想最终尘埃落定
Putting an end to all speculation,
‎亚瑟米勒和玛丽莲梦露 ‎确认他们很快就会结婚
Arthur Miller and Marilyn Monroe confirmed they will soon marry.
‎能告诉我们你们会举行哪种婚礼吗？
Could you tell us what kind of a wedding you're going to have?
‎希望是很安静的那种
Very quiet, I hope.
‎爸爸 这太漂亮了！
Daddy, this is so beautiful!
‎我永远不想离开！
I don't ever wanna leave!
‎这太美了
It's so beautiful.
‎哦 爸爸！
Oh, Daddy!
‎我永远不想离开
I don't ever want to leave.
‎我爱你
I love you.
‎我们爱你
We love you.
‎爸爸 来吧
Daddy, come on.
‎宝宝饿了 他想让他的妈妈吃东西
Baby's hungry. He wants his mama to eat.
‎是吗？
Mm, yeah?
‎宝宝把愿望告诉了我
Baby makes his wishes known.
‎诺玛只是执行宝宝的愿望
Norma's just the vessel.
‎好的
Okay.
‎吃完土豆以后才行
Not after those potatoes.
‎我是你的好女孩吗 爸爸？
Am I your good girl, Daddy?
‎是的 你是我的好女孩 亲爱的
Yeah. You're my good girl, darling.
‎靠过来
Come here.
‎你是我唯一的爱
You're my only love.
‎爸爸 你永远都不会写我的 对吗？
Daddy, you won't ever write about me, will you?
‎亲爱的 当然不写了
Darling, of course not.
‎我为什么要做这种事？
Why would I do such a thing?
‎人们都会这么做
It's what people do.
‎有时吧
Sometimes.
‎作家会
Writers.
‎我不是其他人
I'm not other people.
‎你和我都不是其他普通人
You and I are not other people.
‎亲爱的 你消失的时候会去哪儿？
Darling,
where do you go when you disappear?
‎爸爸…
Daddy…
‎别让我回去
Don't make me go back.
‎我不想再做她了
I never wanna be her again.
‎我上次活着离开了 但也丢了半条命
I got out with my life last time but only just barely.
‎对 她很好
Yeah, she's wonderful.
‎对 她怀孕了很高兴
Yeah, pregnancy agrees with her.
‎甚至连每天的晨吐都让她很高兴
Even morning sickness, she's cheerful about.
‎然后她说
And then she says, "Oh!"
‎“我猜就应该是这样的”
"Well, this is how it's supposed to be, I guess."
‎对 艾斯特总是那么残忍
Yeah. Esther was always so cruel.
‎诺玛不会想变得残忍
It wouldn't occur to Norma to be cruel.
‎如果说我有遗憾…
If I have one regret…
‎那就是时间过得太快了
…it's that time passes so quickly.
‎你这次不会伤害我吧？
You won't hurt me this time, will you?
‎不会做你上次做的事吧？
Not do what you did the last time?
‎我没有
I didn't.
‎-我不是故意的 ‎-你就是故意的
-I didn't mean to. -Yes, you meant to.
‎那是你的决定
It was your decision.
‎你不是同一个孩子
You're not the same baby.
‎你是这个孩子
You're this baby.
‎以前那个是我 一直都是我
That was me. It's always me.
‎他爱我们
He loves us.
‎他愿意为我们而死
He would die for us.
‎他是这么说的
He said so.
‎花让人们觉得自己受欢迎
Flowers make people feel welcome.
‎让他们有被需要的感觉
Like they're wanted.
‎亲爱的 你把花剪得太短了
Mm, darling, you cut 'em a little too short. See?
‎我做了…什么？
What did I… What?
‎别担心 我们能弥补
Well, don't worry, we can repair the damage. Hmm?
‎来这儿
Come here.
‎诺玛去哪儿了？
Where's Norma gone to?
‎她太可爱了 她跟我想象的完全不同
She's absolutely adorable. She's nothing like I expected.
‎-她博览群书 ‎-对 比如她读过鲁比的书
She's so well-read.
Yeah, like she's read Rudy's book.
‎我太开心有人看过了
I'm just glad somebody has.
‎看看那个 天啊 你…
Look at that out there. Oh my God. Do you guys see that?
‎-你能看见那个吗？ ‎-太美了
‎这太令人难以置信了
This is incredible.
‎亲爱的…
Darling…
‎你不和我们一起去海滩吗？
Aren't you gonna come down to the beach with us?
‎你为什么躲在这里？
Why you hiding in here?
‎我会过去的 爸爸 我只是…
I'm coming, Daddy. I was just…
‎亲爱的 没必要 ‎因为他们的来访而如此紧张
Darling, it isn't necessary to make so much of this visit.
‎你认识鲁比和珍
You know Rudy and Jean.
‎但他们不喜欢我
But they don't like me.
‎他们是来见你的
They've come to see you.
‎诺玛 别无理取闹了
Norma, stop being so ridiculous.
‎你知道他们是来见我们俩的
You know they've come to see us both.
‎亲爱的 跟我下去吧 好吗？ ‎他们等着呢
Darling, come down there with me, huh, will ya? They're waiting.
‎嘿
Hey.
‎跟我出去吧
Come out there with me.
‎你看起来很美
You're looking very beautiful.
‎来吧 好吗？来
-Come, yeah? Come.
‎你还好吗 亲爱的？
You all right, darling?
‎我给他们拿点啤酒去
I'll bring them the beer.
‎我没事
I'm okay.
‎帮帮我
Help me.
‎帮帮我 救救我的孩子
Help me. Save my baby.
‎拜托爸爸 帮帮我！救救宝宝！
Please, Daddy, help me! Deliver the baby!
‎-爸爸！爸爸 救命！ ‎-诺玛！
-Daddy! Daddy, help! -Norma!
‎我想要你的爱
‎只有你 除了你没有其他人
‎我只想要你的爱
‎我想要你的吻
‎只有你 除了你没有其他人
‎我只想要你的吻
‎我不能期盼
‎更高的要求
‎只想填满我的欲望
‎让你成为我的…
‎我想要你的爱
‎只有你 除了你没有其他人
‎我只想要你的爱…
‎你觉得我太蠢了 ‎无法理解你们说的关于我的玩笑吗？
You think I'm too dumb to comprehend the joke's on me?
‎-什么玩笑？ ‎-弹簧上的果冻！
-What joke? -Jell-O on springs!
‎玛丽莲…
Marilyn…
‎-不 玛丽莲！ ‎-我不需要这个！
-No! No! No, no, no, Marilyn! -I don't need this!
‎-出去！ ‎-老天爷！玛丽莲！
-Get out! -For God's sake! Marilyn!
‎-你还好吗？ ‎-我受不了了
-You okay? -I can't take it.
‎-我知道 玛丽莲 ‎-我受不了了！
-I know. -I can't take it!
‎来 亲爱的 我带你去后台
I'll take you in the back here.
‎-给你准备了点东西 ‎-我一会就到
-We got something for you. -Be there in a second.
‎-来吧 平静下来 ‎-我会去的
-Settle down. -I'll be there in a minute.
‎来吧 甜心 来这儿 你做得非常好
Come on, sweetie. Over here. You're doing such a good job.
‎做得太棒了 来这儿
Such a good job. Come on in here. Come on, come on, come on. How about here?
‎比利 她现在不太健康
-Billy? -Hmm?
She's not a well girl. Hmm?
‎如果她能好起来 她就会很好
If she could be well, she would be.
‎没事 亲爱的 有我在
It's okay, honey. I have you. I have you.
‎没事 深呼吸
-It's okay. Breathe.
‎没事
It's okay.
‎就这样 玛丽莲 就这样 甜心
That's it, Marilyn. That's it, sweetie.
‎只要保持不动就好 这…你之前见过
Only just hold still. It's… You've seen it before.
‎等等
Just a minute.
‎-没事 好了 坚持一下 ‎-好的
-It's okay, here you go. Just hold on. -It's okay.
‎好的 就这样
Okay. That's it.
‎深呼吸
Just breathe.
‎-我没事 ‎-看吧？
-I'm okay. -See?
‎我没事
I'm okay.
‎需要帮忙吗 亲爱的？
What can I do to help you, darling?
‎帮我们？
To help us?
‎缅因州那件事之后的每一天
Yeah, every day since Maine,
‎我觉得我们渐行渐远
I feel like we're getting more and more distant.
‎我很担心你 亲爱的
I'm so worried about you, darling.
‎你的健康 这些药物…
Your health. And these drugs…
‎你是想毁了自己吗 诺玛？
Are you trying to destroy yourself, Norma?
‎你对你的人生做了什么？
I mean, what are you doing to your life?
‎我的生活关你什么事？
What business of yours is my life?
‎甜心 你这是自找麻烦
You're gonna get yourself into a lot of trouble.
‎对 你最好留意一下
Yes, you better keep a lookout.
‎如果比恩斯托克再抓到你…
If Bienstock catches you again…
‎-而且你到底怎么回事啊？ ‎-我猜我不太聪明
-What's the matter with you anyway? -I'm not very bright, I guess.
‎我不会这么说 也许该说粗心大意
I wouldn't say that. Careless, maybe.
‎不 就是蠢 如果我有…
No, just dumb. If I had any…
‎如果我有脑子 ‎就不会和这个破女子乐队
If I had any brains, I wouldn't be on this crummy train
‎上这辆破火车了
with this crummy girl's band.
‎脑子不是一切
Brains aren't everything.
‎它只是个动静脉网络 支撑我们存活
You know, it's just a network of veins, arteries… holding us together.
‎如果它们破裂了 就会开始流血
And if they burst, they start bleeding.
‎停！
And cut!
‎操！
Fuck!
‎操你妈！这他妈的电影！
Fuck you! And fuck this movie!
‎亲爱的？
Hon?
‎-医生？ ‎-我在这儿
-Doc? -Right here.
‎怀特利？
Whitey?
‎-来这儿 ‎-嗨 亲爱的
-Come here, come here. -Hi, sweetie. Hi.
‎来点苯丙胺 可待因？
Have a little Benzedrine. Codeine?
‎-你没事 亲爱的 ‎-我想回家
-You're okay. -I wanna go home.
‎-我想回家 ‎-如果你能熬过去吗？
-I wanna go home. -What if you get through this?
‎我想回家！
I wanna go home! I wanna go home! I wanna go home!
I wanna go home!
‎我听说了你的悲惨遭遇
Having heard of your tragic loss,
‎我谨表示衷心的哀悼
I wish to offer my heartfelt condolences.
‎未出生的灵魂的死亡 ‎可能会让我们加倍痛苦
The death of an unborn soul may lodge more painfully within us.
‎那么多人 太多人了！
So many people. It's just so many!
‎为什么上帝造了那么多人？
Why did God make so many?
‎因为纯真的灵魂是未经污染的
'Cause the innocence is unsullied.
‎当然 现在媒体已经报道了此事
Of course, it has been in the press by now.
‎我很快就会亲自联系你的
I will contact you soon in person.
‎看 诺玛简…
See, Norma Jeane…
‎那男人是你的父亲
that man is your father.
‎我很快就会联系你的 我保证
Soon I will contact you, I promise.
‎看 诺玛简 那男人是你的父亲
See, Norma Jeane, that man is your father.
‎我能解释我们关系的情况
I can explain the circumstances of our relationship
‎我们要亲自见面谈
when we meet face-to-face.
‎“你泪流满面、慈爱的父亲”
"Your tearful and loving father."
‎你是谁？
Who are you?
‎亲爱的 我是你的丈夫
Darling, I'm… I'm your husband.
‎你好
Hello.
‎梦露小姐 你今天要来吗？
Miss Monroe, are you coming in today?
‎不
No.
‎玛丽莲梦露今天 ‎不会来冒充且贬低自己
Marilyn Monroe will not be coming in today to impersonate and demean herself.
‎你不得不拍她周围的人或者景
And you will have to shoot around her.
‎怀特利？
Whitey? Whitey?
‎我发誓 我一小时 ‎就能给玛丽莲准备好
I'm going to conjure Marilyn within the hour, I promise.
‎抱一个 一切都会好起来的
Come here. It's gonna be all right.
‎好的 很好
Okay. Good.
‎宝宝没了
Baby's gone.
‎宝宝没了 怀特利
Baby's gone, Whitey.
‎我知道
I know.
‎没事的
It'll be okay.
‎梦露小姐
Oh, Miss Monroe.
‎好的
Okay.
‎请过来
Here.Please come.
‎请过来 别抛弃我
Please come. Don't abandon me.
‎-求你了 ‎-她来了
-Please. -She's coming.
‎请来吧
Please come.
‎她来了
She's coming.
‎-别抛弃我 ‎-她来了
-Don't abandon me. -She's coming.
‎她快到了
-She's almost here.
‎请过来
Please come.
‎玛丽莲！
-Marilyn! Marilyn!
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎玛丽莲！
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎玛丽莲！
Marilyn! Marilyn!
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎（玛丽莲梦露出演比利怀尔德的 ‎《热情似火》）
Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn! Marilyn!
‎我爱你们 我爱你们所有人
I love you. I love, love, love you all.
‎人无完人
Well, nobody's perfect.
‎（剧终）
‎（1962年）
‎要香槟吗 梦露小姐？
Champagne, Miss Monroe?
‎要一点点
Yeah, just a little.
‎这能帮助我入眠
Oh, it's just to help me sleep.
‎我经常看到你美丽的脸庞
I see your beautiful face often.
‎我想知道你怎么保养得那么好
And I wonder how you look so…
…untouched.
‎但我猜灵魂并不总是显露在脸上
But the soul does not always show in the face, I suppose.
‎已经过去太多年了
Too many years have slipped away.
‎我必须见你 我美丽而迷茫的女儿
And I must see you, my beautiful lost daughter.
‎在我踏上那漫长的漂洋过海的旅程前
Before I embark on that long journey across the sea.
‎你泪流满面的父亲
Your tearful father.
‎梦露小姐
Miss Monroe.
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe?
‎剧院里真热
It's so hot in this theater.
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe? Miss Monroe?
‎嗨 梦露小姐？
Hi, Miss Monroe?
‎我们已经在纽约降落了
We've landed in New York.
‎我们到了 对 让我来帮你
We're here. Yeah. Let me help you.
‎我可以帮你拿外套
I can take your coat.
-给，拿着 我带她去
Here, take this. I'll get her to customs.
‎准备好了吗？一、二
Ready? One, two.
‎-好 ‎-小心头
-Yeah. -Oh, watch your head.
‎没事
It's okay.
‎我们这边走
Let's go this way.
‎好的
Okay.
‎快到了
Almost there.
‎我被捕了吗？
Am I under arrest?
‎我会遇到什么事？
What will happen to me?
‎梦露小姐？
Miss Monroe?
‎梦露小姐？别躺在这儿 好吗？
Miss Monroe? You don't wanna lay down here. Okay?
‎拜托
Please.
‎-来吧 ‎-我们扶住她了 起来吧
-Come on. -We got her. Up you come.
‎总统和我之间不是性关系
It isn't sexual between the president and me.
‎跟性无关
It has very little to do with sex.
‎这是我们灵魂的相遇
It's a meeting of our souls.
‎我刚刚大声说出来了吗？
Oh. Did I say that out loud?
‎女士 你今晚回洛杉矶的票
Your ticket, ma'am, for your return to LA this evening.
‎今晚？但是…
This evening? But…
‎总统行程变了 女士 ‎所以你的行程也变了
President's plans have changed, ma'am, so your plans have changed.
‎有紧急情况 需要他回华盛顿
There's an emergency situation calling him back to Washington.
‎毕竟他不能过夜
He can't stay overnight after all.
‎我知道了
Oh, I see.
‎-退后 退回去 ‎-请给我们一点空间
-Step back. -Give us some space.
‎后退
Get back.
‎该死！天啊！
Goddamn it! Jesus!
‎-去别的地方 让开 ‎-我们需要一些空间 借过
-Go somewhere else. Clear. -We need some room. Excuse us.
‎小心楼梯 女士
Watch your step, ma'am.
‎小心
-Watch it.
‎来吧 女士 跟上来 女士
Come on, ma'am. Step along, please, ma'am.
‎我可以自己走 谢谢 我没残废
I can walk myself. Thank you. I'm not crippled.
‎天啊！
Oh my God!
‎我就该被押送过去吗？ ‎这算什么？客房服务吗？
Am I meat to be delivered? Is that what this is? Room service?
‎等等
Hang on.
‎你需要补妆吗 梦露小姐？
Would you wish to freshen up, Miss Monroe?
‎天啊
Oh God.
‎这边 梦露小姐
This way, Miss Monroe.
‎这里
Right here.
‎女士
Ma'am.
‎这边 梦露小姐
This way, Miss Monroe.
‎我们把梦露小姐带到了 先生
We have Miss Monroe here, sir.
‎问题是？
The matter being?
‎知道了
-I see.
‎那这个男人是谁呢？
And just who might this man be?
‎很高兴见到你 宝贝 ‎今天真是糟透了
Am I glad to see you, baby. This has been one hell of a day.
‎天啊 我听说了 亲爱的
Oh, gosh, I've been told, darling.
‎我能怎么帮你吗？
How can I help?
‎若你看过照片 ‎就会知道她一点也不“普通”
If you've got pictures, you'll see she can hardly be called "common."
‎你也不需要教训我 先生
Nor will you lecture me, sir.
‎宝贝 别害羞 来吧
Baby. Don't be shy. Come on, come on.
‎总统先生
-Mr. President.
‎-总统先生 ‎-别害羞 来吧
- Mr. President. -Don't be shy. Come on.
‎总统先生 德克萨斯州的 ‎一位州长助理指控你骚扰她
Mr. President, a gubernatorial aide in Texas alleges you molested her.
‎联邦调查局还发现了一个白宫官员
The Bureau has also uncovered a member of White House personnel
‎愿意出庭作证 ‎称你和她有不正当性关系
willing to testify that you and she conducted an inappropriate sexual liaison.
‎这些女性 总统先生 ‎这些指控不仅对总统办公室造成了…
These women, these allegations, they not only inflict irreparable harm…
‎-宝贝 快 ‎-…无法弥补的伤害 还威胁到美国
-Baby, come on. -…on the presidency, but also on America.
‎我的私生活与任何人无关
My personal life is no one's business but my own.
‎谁把我带到了这地方的？
Who brought me here
to this place?
‎是玛丽莲吗？
Was it Marilyn?
‎但为什么玛丽莲要做这些事？ ‎玛丽莲想要什么？
But why does Marilyn do these things?
What does Marilyn want?
‎还是说这是电影片段？
Or is it a movie scene?
‎我在扮演一个著名的金发女郎
I'm playing the part of a famous blonde actress
‎与自由世界里英俊潇洒的领导人见面
meeting the boyishly handsome leader of the free world,
‎与美国总统来一次浪漫约会
the President of the United States, for a romantic rendezvous.
‎“无害的姑娘”出演无害的软色情片
The girl upstairs in harmless soft porn film.
‎只此一次 为什么不呢？ ‎任何场景都可以演
Just once. Why not? Any scene can be played.
‎无论演得好坏 都可以演
Whether well or badly, it can be played.
‎而且它不会超过几分钟
And it won't last more than a few minutes.
‎你这个肮脏的荡妇
Dirty slut. Oh! Oh, you dirty slut.
‎别吐
Just don't puke.
‎别吐在这儿 别吐床上
- Not here. Not in this bed.
‎别咳 别作呕 你得吞下去
Don't cough. Don't gag.
You have to swallow.
‎-你得吞下去 ‎-你这肮脏的女孩…
-You have to swallow. -Oh, you dirty girl…
‎宝贝！
Oh, baby!
‎你…太棒了
Yes. Ah, fantastic.
‎总统先生…
Mr. President… Mr. President…
‎这些女人 总统先生…
These women, Mr. President…
‎这些指控…
These allegations,
‎对美国造成了无法挽回的伤害
they inflict irreparable harm on America.
‎总统先生
Mr. President.
‎天啊 普龙托 这些女孩？
Gee, Pronto, these girls?
‎天啊 我知道你是个成熟的男人 ‎我也不是小孩子
Gosh, I know you're a man of the world.
I'm not a child.
‎你不必担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
‎梦露…梦露小姐
Monroe… Miss Monroe.
‎来吧 起来
-Get up. Get… Just…
Come on. Just get up.
‎-天啊 把她拉起来 ‎-我抱住她了 来吧
-Oh, Jesus. Grab her. -I got her. Come on.
‎梦露小姐 这边 你需要帮助吗？
Miss Monroe, this way, ma'am. Do you need assistance?
‎我爱总统
I love the president.
‎-女士？ ‎-不用 我没事
Ma'am?
No. I'm fine.
‎请别进来
Don't come inside, please.
‎-梦露小姐！怎么了？ ‎-天啊 怀特利 我还以为我死了
Miss Monroe! What's wrong? What's wrong?
Oh, gosh, Whitey. I thought I was dead.
‎-你刚刚在打瞌睡 ‎-只是一秒钟
-You just dozed off. -Just for a second.
‎-天啊 ‎-别闹了
Oh God.
Oh, stop.
‎你觉得你…你看起来是像死了一样
And you thought you were… You look dead.
‎-我需要这个 ‎-天啊 来一点
-I need this. -My God. Have it.
‎你还好吗？
You all right?
‎别叫了
Stop screaming.
‎你是谁？
Who is it?
‎你做出的牺牲…
The circle of light is yours.
‎你把自己置于圈中 ‎无论你走到哪儿都带着它
You enclose yourself in the circle. You carry it with you wherever you go.
‎这光圈是你的
The circle of light is yours.
‎你把自己置于圈中 ‎无论你走到哪儿都带着它
You enclose yourself in the circle. You carry it with you wherever you go.
‎这只是个梦
It's just a dream. It's just a dream.
It's just a dream.
‎这只是个梦 这只是…
It's just a dream. It's just a…
‎这只是个疯狂的梦
It's just a crazy dream.
‎天啊 多丑陋的梦啊
Oh Christ.
What an ugly dream.
‎多疯狂的梦啊
What a crazy dream.
‎我不想变得残忍
I have not intended to be cruel.
‎也不想玩弄你的心
Or to toy with your heart.
‎我因生病而无法正常活动
I have been incapacitated by illness.
‎但你经常出现在我脑海中
But you are in my thoughts often.
‎我只在远处了解你
I have known you only at a distance.
‎这么多年过去了 ‎我们的距离似乎无法跨越
Years passed, and that distance seemed too great to surmount.
‎时间就是阻挡在我们之间的鸿沟
Time is like a fast river running through us.
‎已经如此…
Already it isn't.
‎我发誓我很快就会联系你
Soon I will contact you, I promise.
‎好 但你为什么等待？
Yes. Yes, but why are you waiting?
‎你泪流满面的父亲
Your tearful father.
诺玛…
-Norma…
‎我是艾迪G
It's Eddy G.
‎卡西死了
Cass is dead.
‎被呕吐物噎住 窒息而亡 ‎经典的醉酒死法 对吧？
Choked on his puke and strangled. Classic alky death, huh?
‎我今早过来的时候发现了他的遗体
I found him when I came over this morning.
‎卡西给你留了个纪念品 诺玛
Cass left a memento for you, Norma.
‎他大部分的东西都留给我了
Most of his things, he left to me.
‎我是他的好兄弟 从没让他失望
I was his good buddy, never let him down, so he left most of his things to me.
‎所以他把大部分东西留给了我
‎但这个纪念品
But this memento…
‎他说：“这东西某天要给诺玛”
…"This is for Norma someday," he'd say.
‎这对他来说意义非凡
It meant a lot to him.
‎他说：“诺玛总是让我心动”
"Norma always had my heart," he'd say.
‎不
No.
‎“不”什么？
"No" what?
‎我不想要
I don't want it.
‎-我不想要 艾迪 ‎-你怎么知道你不想要呢 诺玛？
I don't want it, Eddy.
How do you know you don't want it, Norma?
‎你不知道这是什么东西
You don't know what it is.
‎好吧 宝贝 我会寄过去
Right, baby. I'll send it.
‎记得查特别快递
Look for special delivery.
‎（玛丽莲）
‎谢谢
Thank you.
‎等等
Oh, just a minute.
‎我的钱包呢？
Where's my wallet?
‎不在我的手提袋里？
Not in my purse?
‎我放哪儿去了？
Where did I put it?
‎但你也想让那孩子死
But you wanted baby dead too.
‎你知道你想
You know you did.
‎（诺玛简）
‎（致我的女儿）
‎（从来就没有什么泪流满面的父亲 ‎爱你的 卡西）
‎诺玛简 看
Norma Jeane, look.
‎那男人是你的父亲
That man is your father.
‎（改编自乔伊斯卡罗尔欧茨的小说）
‎（若你或你认识的人正在经历挣扎）
感谢匡思颖